真爱字幕组
行尸走肉  前情回顾
Previously on AMC's The Walking Dead...
- Gabriel  - 你说你有个教堂
- Gabriel... - You said you had a church.
我不相信这家伙
I don't trust this guy.
他有所隐瞒
He's hiding something.
这是个储粮库  粮济全郡
This was the food bank. Served the whole county.
- 我们去救Gabriel  - 怎么了？
- We have to get Gabriel. - What happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们要带Eugene去华盛顿
We get Eugene to Washington,
他可以了结这一切
and he will make the dead die
人类将重获世界
and the living will have this world again.
我们也去！就这样
We're in! Let's do it.
好消息是  你还没死
Good news is, you're not dead.
但一日将过
But at the end of the day,
人总得进食啊
a man's got to eat.
也许在这儿待着很蠢
It's probably pretty stupid to be here.
危机四伏
Dangerous.
我不知道  也许不是
I don't know, maybe not.
你能看到威胁
You can see the threat.
就那些
That's something.
看着它们会让我觉得好受点儿
Looking at them makes me feel better about things.
我母亲常说
My mom used to say that
活一天就胜一场
every day above ground was a win.
太他妈有道理了  但是
Doesn't really apply anymore, but...
你还可以看长远点
you can still get some perspective.
这玻璃早晚会碎
The glass is gonna break sooner or later.
没什么会永垂不朽
Nothing lasts too long anymore.
我们一路做标记
You know, we marked our way here
所以就能找到回去的路
so that we could find our way back after.
太二了  是吧？我是说…
So stupid, right? I mean...
回哪儿？
back to what?
它不仅是个陷阱
It wasn't just a trap.
也是一次选择
It was gonna be a choice.
加入我们  或被我们吃
You join us or feed us.
你知道
You know...
熊这种生物…
bears...
要是挨饿了
when they start to starve,
就会食子
they eat their young.
要是大熊死了  幼崽还是死
If the bear dies, the cub dies anyway.
但如果大熊活下来了
But if the bear lives,
还能再生幼崽
it can always have another cub.
说跑偏了
That was part of the pitch.
你知道的  Greg和Mike过来
You know, Greg and Mike came this close
是为了抓那个
to nabbing that grey-haired queen bitch
杀了我母亲的白发婊子
who killed my mom.
她和弩哥开车走了
She drove away with the archer.
Greg看到他们扬尘而去
Greg saw them pull away.
等不及想尝尝她了
Can't wait to try her.
我更喜欢女人
I like women better.
我们大多都是
Most of us do.
我弟弟Alex曾…
My brother Alex has--
因为Rick  他现在也不在了
also currently dead because of Rick--
他曾说过这个理论
he had a theory that it was
女人因为生育
because of the extra layer of fat
皮下脂肪多一层  你懂的
that women have, you know, for childbearing.
就算是骨感美女也是
Even the skinny girls have it.
像漂亮的…Sasha？
Like that pretty one-- Sasha?
我觉得好看的也会更好吃
I think pretty people taste better, too.
我们会抓住他们的
We're going to get all of them.
但对于初学者  你很不错了
But for starters, you'll do just fine.
你腿就贡献良多
We did a good job on your leg.
我们慢慢练
We've had practice.
一旦学起来  就得放慢进程了
When we started, it was about making it slow.
我是个人啊  在和你说话
I'm being a human being here. I'm talking to you.
看清形势  Bob
Perspective, Bob.
你还在地上坐着
You're above ground.
至少比他们强多了
At least you're better off than them.
好吧  他疯了
Well, he lost it.
比我想象的疯得晚
Lasted longer than I thought he would.
你们…
You...
一群大傻逼
you idiots.
好吧  放下
Okay, keep it down.
我可以让他闭嘴
I can shut him up.
我被咬了  你们这帮傻叉！
I've been bitten, you stupid pricks!
我被感染了
I'm tainted meat.
- 让我宰了他  - 不  我们需要他
- Let's just kill him now. - No, no, we need him.
我们可吃了丧尸肉啊
We might as well be eating one of them.
那会发生什么啊？
What the hell's gonna happen?
会转化吗？  会死吗？
Are we gonna turn? Are we just gonna die?
Albert  他妈冷静  我们烹饪过
Albert, calm the hell down. We cooked him.
没事的
Everything is gonna be fine.
你他妈为什么不先检查下？
Why the hell didn't you check him first?
因为他好好的
'Cause he was fine.
- 感染肉啊！ - 闭嘴
- Tainted meat! - Shut up.
- 你们吃了丧尸肉！ - 我说了闭嘴！
- You eating tainted meat! - I said shut up!
行 尸 走 肉
第五季第三集
Bob
Bob.
翻译  校对：老马  幸福ing
翻译  校对：BBgun
实习翻译：小米  啊呕
监制  后期：幸福ing形式
是我  是我
It's me. It's me.
Tyreese
Tyreese.
- 他走了  - 谁？
- He's getting away. - Who?
有人在监视我们
Somebody was watching us.
如果现在进去
If we go in there now,
估计就有人出不来了
some of us aren't coming back.
Bob就在外面什么地方
Bob is out there somewhere.
害怕  孤独
Scared, alone.
也许不是独自一人
Maybe not alone.
Daryl和Carol也不见了
Daryl and Carol are missing, too.
别动
Stop.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
这就对上号了
This is all connected.
你一出现
You show up,
我们就被监视了
we're being watched,
现在我们有三个人都不见了
and now three of us are gone.
我…
I...
我没…
I don't...
我跟这事没一点关系
I don't have anything to do with this.
- 等等！ - 别！
- Wait! - Don't!
- Sasha  收起来  - 谁在外面？
- Sasha, put it away. - Who's out there?
我  我跟这…
I-- I don't have anything...
- 没有一点关系  - 我们的人呢？
- to do with this. - Where are our people?
- 我跟这事没  - 我们的人呢？
- I don't have anything to-- - Where are our people?!
求你了  我跟这事没一点关系
Please, I don't have anything to do with this.
我…
I--
你为什么把我们带到这？
Why'd you bring us here?
求你了  我…
Please, I--
你跟谁一起工作？
You working with someone?
我一个人  我自己
I'm alone. I'm alone.
我一直一个人
I was always alone.
那个储粮库的女人呢  Gabriel？
What about the woman in the food bank, Gabriel?
你对她做了什么？
What did you do to her?
“你会被这一切焚尽”
"You'll burn for this."
是你写的吧  为什么？
That was for you. Why?
为了什么被焚啊  Gabriel？
What are you gonna burn for, Gabriel?
说？  你做了什么？
What? What did you do?
你过去做了什么？！
What did you do?!
我晚上把门关上了
I lock the doors at night.
我经常晚上把门关上的
I always lock the doors at night.
我经常…
I always--
他们陆续过来  我的子民们
They started coming, my congregation.
之前亚特兰大在晚上被轰炸了
Atlanta was bombed the night before
所以他们害怕了
and they were scared.
他们…他们在寻找一个安全的地方
They were-- they were looking for a safe place,
一个他们觉得安全的地方
a place where they felt safe.
那会儿还早  很早
And it was so early. It was so early.
所以门还关着
And the doors were still locked.
你看…
You see...
这是我的选择
it was my choice.
他们人太多了
There were so many of them
他们试图撬开百叶窗
and they were trying to pry the shutters
使劲撞击侧面  冲我叫唤
and banging on the sidings, screaming at me.
所以那些行尸就向他们去了
And so the dead came for them.
妇人…
Women...
孩子
children.
所有人痛苦的喊着我的名字
Entire families calling my name as they were torn apart,
请求我的怜悯
begging me for mercy.
Begging me for mercy.
我该下地狱啊
Damning me to hell.
我焚烧了他们的尸骨
I buried their bones.
都烧了
I buried it all.
主最终还是让你来惩罚我了
The Lord sent you here to finally punish me.
我该死
I'm damned.
我之前该死
I was damned before.
我经常锁着门
I always lock the doors.
锁着门
那儿有…
There's something--
玻璃外有人躲着
there's someone outside lying in the grass.
Sasha
Sasha.
Bob！
Oh! Bob!
Bob
Bob.
他的腿  - 把Bob带进去
His leg. - Get Bob inside.
我们会照顾好他们的
We'll take care of them.
你能帮帮我吗  求你了？
Can you help me, please?
帮帮我  帮帮我
Help me. Help me.
进去！
Get inside!
快去！
Go!
我之前在墓地
I was in the graveyard.
有人把我打晕了
Somebody knocked me out.
我刚醒来就在这里了
I woke up outside this place.
那看起来像个学校
It looked like a school.
是那个人  Gareth
It was that guy, Gareth.
还有其他5个人
And five other ones.
他们在我面前吃我的腿
They were eating my leg right in front of me.
就像这没什么一样
Like it was nothing.
就像无比自豪的了结了一切
All proud like they had it all figured out.
她们抓了Daryl和Carol吗？
Did they have Daryl and Carol?
Gareth说他们开车走了
Gareth said they drove off.
他很痛  有什么能用的？
He's in pain. Do we have anything?
我觉得急救箱里应该有药品
I think there are pill packets in the first aid kit.
- 恩  - 留着吧
- Yeah. - Save 'em.
- 不  - 说真的
- No. - Really.
我在储粮库时被咬了
It happened at the food bank.
没事的
It's okay.
Bob
Bob?
我办公室里有个沙发
There's a sofa in my office.
我知道这不算什么  但…
I know it's not much, but...
谢谢你
Thank you.
我来吧
I got him.
你知道Bob说的那个地方吗？
Do you know the place Bob was talking about?
是个小学
It's an elementary school.
- 离这儿很近  - 多近？
- It's close. - How close?
多近啊  Gabriel？
How close, Gabriel?
从这走十分钟  穿过树林就到了
It's just a 10-minute walk through the woods from here,
在墓地的正南方
due south of the graveyard.
嘘
Shh, shh, shh.
他是发烧了吗？
Does he have a fever?
只是有点热
He's just warm.
Jim大概活了两天
Jim lasted almost two days
之后我们就丢下他了
before we left him.
该面对现实了
Time for a reality check.
我们现在全部都要去特区
We all need to leave for DC right now.
Daryl和Carol会回来的
Daryl and Carol are gonna be back.
没有他们我们哪儿都不去
We're not going anywhere without them.
我赞赏你的态度
I respect that,
但明显现在Eugene有危险
but there's a clear threat here to Eugene.
我得保护好他  防止事态恶化
I need to extract his ass before things get any uglier.
如果你们不愿意来  祝你们好运
So if y'all won't come, good luck to you.
你们做你们的  我做我的
We'll go our separate ways.
你就打算步行吗？
You leaving on foot?
我们把那辆车修好了
We fixed that damn bus ourselves.
我们这儿的人还有那么多
There are a lot more of us.
你就想一直这样吗？你来啊
You want to keep it that way? You should come.
Carol救了你的命  我们救了你的命
Carol saved your life. We saved your life.
而我是在救你们大家命
Well, I am trying to save yours.
救每个人的
Save everyone's.
我们是不会分头行动的
We're not going anywhere without our people.
真
爱
字
幕
组
- 你们的人都逃了  - 他们会回来的
- Your people took off. - They're coming back.
回来干啥？来看你们剩下的骨头吗？
To what, picked-over bones?!
- 你还没明白  - 别碰我！
- You're not taking - Do not lay hands!
- Abraham！- 喂  打住！打住！
- Abraham! - Hey, hey, stop! Now!
你真的觉得  你大半夜的这样离开
Do you really think that you're gonna be any safer
你就会更安全吗？
leaving right now in the middle of the night?
对啊
Yeah.
就是这样
那明天呢？
What about tomorrow?
我们要团结才能做到
We need each other for this.
要团结才能到达特区
We need each other to get to DC.
我们团结就可以渡过这一切
We can get through all of it together.
我有个想法
I have an idea.
如果你多待一天帮助我们
If you stay just one more day and help,
我和你们去特区  不论发生什么
I'll go with you to DC no matter what.
好吗？
Okay?
Glenn和Maggie也来
Glenn and Maggie, too.
- 不行  - 那祝你们好运
- No. - Good luck, then.
我对你们的人也不感兴趣
I'm not interested in breaking up what you have here.
Rosita 抄起你的家伙
Rosita, grab your gear.
- Abraham  - 少废话！
- Abraham - Now.
Euegne  我们走  Euegne
Eugene, let's go. Eugene.
起来
Move it.
- 我不想  - 快起来！
- I don't want to. - Now.
好吧
Okay.
你不能用那辆公车
You're not taking the bus.
试着拦下我啊！
Try to stop me.
慢着  慢着
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
喂 喂
Hey, hey, hey!
你留下来
You stay--
留下来帮助我们
you stay and help us,
然后我们就跟你走
and we will go with you.
- 不  - 这不是你说了算
- No. - It's not your call.
你留下来帮我们
You stay, help us.
就半天
Half a day.
正午走  时间紧迫
Come high noon, we're taillights.
我不会再多等了
I'm not waiting for the other damn shoe to drop.
我们会和你走的
And we will leave with you.
12个小时
12 hours.
我们就走
Then we go.
其实  我脸上被打
You know, the one good thing
有一个好处
about getting kicked in my face--
就是让我忘了腿上的疼痛
made me forget the pain in my leg.
还有我半身的疼痛  所以是两个好处
And my side, so two good things.
别再说傻话了
We're not playing that game anymore.
恩…
Well...
从各面考虑
all things considered,
我觉得你可以逗我笑一下
figured you could humor me a little bit.
被咬后
Why didn't you tell me
为什么不告诉我？
when it happened?
我知道
I knew
我告诉你的话
when I told you,
就会像一切都结束了
it'd become all about the end.
而我很享受这个过程
And I really liked the middle.
他们以为他们掌控了局面
They think they're in control.
我们在明  他们在暗
We're in here and they could be anywhere.
但我们知道他们的确切位置
But we know exactly where they are.
计划受阻  我只能这么说
Plan's got stones, I'll give you that.
- 我们得赶在他们前面　- 没错
- Make our move before they do. - That's right.
他们不指望我们头脑清晰
They're not counting on us thinking straight.
有吗？
Are we?
我只想确认一下　这可不是件小事
I'm just making sure. It's a big play.
时刻记得提防这些人
Remember what these people are capable of.
- Tyreese  - 怎么了？
- Tyreese. - Yeah?
你准备好了吗？
You up for this?
我和你们一起去
I'm going with you.
你应该和Bob呆一块儿
You should stay with Bob.
不　我想出去
No, I want to be out there.
我想参与进来
I want to be a part of this.
我知道这是什么感觉
I know how it feels.
但是在这里
But this right here,
你可以和他在一起
the time you could have with him,
你不能错过这个机会
you can't throw that away.
真希望我和Karen有这样的机会
I wish I had it with Karen.
你还记得当时的感受吗？
Do you remember how you felt?
还有你当时想做的事？
What you wanted to do?
是
Yeah.
那让我迷茫
It made it so I couldn't see it.
饶恕
Forgiveness.
勇敢面对
That's facing it.
我应该饶恕他们吗？
I should forgive them?
真爱字幕组
就算伤害他  想要杀了我们？
For hurting him? For trying to kill us?
你到底怎么了？
What the hell is wrong with you?
你觉得我们还有选择吗？
You think we have a choice?
不是所有的人都能选择
Not all of us.
只有你有
Just you.
他睁开眼
When he opens his eyes,
唯一想看到的就是你的脸
the only thing he's gonna want to see is your face.
拿着
Take it.
- 如果他停止呼吸…　　- Sasha
- If he stops breathing... - Sasha.
…你把这个穿过他的太阳穴
...you put it through his temple.
这是Bob想要的
That's what Bob would want.
我想你知道我们在这
Well, I guess you know we're here.
我们也知道你们在这
And we know you're here.
而且我们武器齐全
And we're armed.
所有没必要躲躲藏藏了
So there's really no point in hiding anymore.
我们一直在监视你们
We've been watching you.
我们知道都有谁在
We know who's here.
Bob在
There's Bob,
如果你们还没结束他的痛苦
unless you've put him out of his misery already.
还有Eugene
And Eugene.
Rosita
Rosita.
Martin的好朋友Tyreese
Martin's good friend Tyreese.
Carl
Carl.
Judith
Judith.
Rick和其他人出去了
Rick and the rest walked out
拿着你们大部分枪
with a lot of your guns.
听着　我们不知道你们在哪里
Listen, we don't know where you all are,
但是这个地方不大
but this isn't a big place.
所以现在别闹了
So let's just stop this now
别把事情搞得更糟糕
before things get more painful than they need to be.
听着　你们就躲在某一扇门后
Look, you're behind one of these two doors
我们手上武器干掉你们
and we have more than enough firepower
那是绰绰有余
to take down both.
这应该不是你们想要的吧
Can't imagine that's what you all want.
那个神父怎么样？
How about the priest?
神父　你帮我们把事办好
Father, you help us wrap this up,
我们就让你走
we'll let you walk away from this.
只要把门打开　你就可以走了
Just open the door and you can go.
你可以把小婴儿带走
You can take the baby with you.
你觉得怎么样？
What do you say?
也许我们可以留下这个孩子
I don't know. Maybe we'll keep the kid.
我越来越喜欢这小女孩了
I'm starting to like this girl.
这是你最后的机会了
It's your last chance right now
马上出来
to tell us you're coming out.
完了吗？
Are we done?
把枪放在地板上
Put your guns on the floor.
Rick　我们直接朝那间办公室开枪
Rick, we'll fire right into that office.
你把枪拿低点
So you lower your gun--
啊！
Ah!
把枪放地上　跪下
Put your guns on the floor and kneel.
照他说的做
Do what he says.
Martin　我们没有其他选择了
Martin, there's no choice here.
不　我们还有选择
Yeah, there is.
想打个赌吗？
Want to bet?
求饶也没有意义了　对吧？
No point in begging, right?
是的
No.
你进来的时候　有机会杀掉我们的
Still, you could have killed us when you came in.
为什么
There had to be a reason for that.
我们不想浪费子弹
We didn't want to waste the bullets.
我们以前帮过人
We used to help people.
我们拯救别人
We saved people.
现在变了　他们来了
Things changed. They came in and--
然后
After that...
我知道你在外面呆过　但我也知道
I know that you've been out there, but I can see it.
你不知道饥肠辘辘是何感受
You don't know what it is to be hungry.
你不必这样做
You don't have to do this.
我们可以走得远远的
We can walk away.
我们永无交集
And we will never cross paths again.
我发誓
I promise you.
但你会遇上其他的人
But you'll cross someone's path.
会对其他人做同样的事
You'd do this to anyone,
是吧？
right?
而且
Besides,
我已经给过你承诺了
I already made you a promise.
不！
No!
这可能本是我们的下场
It could have been us.
是
Yeah.
这里可是教堂啊
This is the Lord's house.
不
No.
这仅仅是一个顶盖四面墙
It's just four walls and a roof.
你永远与我们同在
You'll always be with us.
是我们的一员
Part of us.
Rick.
不  不必
No, don't.
就抱着她吧
Let her stay.
她会乖的
I trust her.
我就在门外
I'm right outside.
我想对你说声谢谢
I just want to say thank you.
为什么？
For what?
在我到监狱之前
Before the prison,
我一直不知道世上还有没有好人了
I didn't know if there were any good people left.
我甚至不知道是否还有人活着
I didn't know if anybody was left.
但你加我入伙
You took me in.
是你把人们都凝聚起来了
'Cause you took people in.
是你  伙计
It was you, man.
我昨天所说的
What I said yesterday,
不会改口
I ain't revising it.
就算是现在这种世道
Even in light of current events.
噩梦过后
Nightmares end.
希望你不会在噩梦中迷失自己
They shouldn't end who you are.
这是我这个将死之人想要说的
And that is just this dead man's opinion.
我会记在心里的
I'll take it.
看看她
Just look at her
就好像这个世界未曾改变
and tell me the world isn't gonna change.
你要不行了
You were out.
嗯
Hmm.
是吗？
Was I?
是的
You were.
你为什么在笑？
Why are you smiling?
我好像正在做梦
I think I was dreaming.
而且梦见你
And I think you
对我灿烂地笑着
were smiling back at me in the dream.
对  就像这样
Yeah, that's it.
那这算什么？
So what is it?
是因祸得福吗？
The good that comes out of this bad?
Bob?
让我来吧
Give it here.
你在外面等着
You step out.
好吗？
Okay?
这是我们去特区的路线图
This is our route to DC.
我们沿着这个一直走
We'll stick to it as long as we're able.
如果不行  你们也知道我们在哪
If not, well, you got our destination.
只要Eugene拿到了解药
Once Eugene gets to the big brains left up there,
世界就会复原了
things are gonna bounce back.
这支队伍应该为此而去
This group should be there for it.
你应为此前行
You should be there for it.
他们会的
They will be.
我们会的
We will.
是的  我们会
我们走吧
Let's go.
华盛顿特区
对不起  我混球  来华盛顿吧
新的世界需要Rick Grimes
我还不知道对于你来说
I never asked how it was for you
终点站意味着什么
getting to Terminus.
会杀了我
It killed me.
不  它不会
No, it didn't.
我睡不着
I can't sleep.
现在  坐在这里
And now, sitting in there...
一片寂静
Quiet.
不像昨晚一样
It isn't just what happened last night.
整夜回荡着当时凄惨声音
Saying what happened before...
震耳响亮
out loud...
我能回想那个场景
I see it all again.
那惨叫仿佛就在耳边
I hear them.
对
Yeah.
真爱字幕组
它不会停止
That won't stop.
但总不会一直这样
But it won't be all the time.
Carol去哪了？
Where's Carol?